sound, pronunciation. This is an opportune moment, then, to go into the quality of
your voice. In my observation, when people speak a foreign language, they tense up
their throat, so their whole communication style sounds forced, pinched, strained,
artificial, or nasal. The foreign speaker's voice is also generally higher
pitched than would be considered desirable. To practice the difference
between high pitch and lower pitch, work on uh-oh. In addition to pitch, this
exercise will let you discover between a tinny nasal tone and a deep rich
mellifluous basso profundo tone. The tilde is used to indicate a nasal sound. If you
try to deepen your voice by expanding your throat, you'll end up with an odd hollow
sound.